{"tossups": [{"question": "Jack London\u2019s memoir The Road details his experiences as a hobo traveling with a part of this group. That part of this group was named for Californian general Charles Kelley. The leader of this group named his son \u201cLegal Tender\u201d in response to economic strife. This group expounded their ideals of \u201cGoodwill to men and Death to (*) Interest\u201d while launching their \u201cpetition in boots\u201d. This group\u2019s leader was arrested for trespassing on the White House Lawn. For 10 points, name this quasi-military group named for an Ohio businessman which protested the Panic of 1893.", "answer": "Coxey\u2019s Army ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Coxey\u2019s Army</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Coxey\u2019s Army"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: the answer to this question refers to a non-movement section of a larger musical work. Description acceptable. This section of a larger work is followed by (read slowly) grace notes on A flat, B, then eighth notes on A, G flat, A, G flat, A. This section was meant to emulate the \"steely rhythms\" of a train horn heard on its composer's trip from Boston. This section was improvised by performer Ross Gorman to make its composer laugh.This section begins a piece commissioned 5 weeks before Paul Whiteman's An (*) Experiment in Modern Music concert. For 10 points, name this 17-note woodwind flourish that begins a George Gershwin \"jazz concerto\". ", "answer": "the clarinet glissando from \"Rhapsody in Blue\" [both answers required, prompt on partial answer, prompt on \"Rhapsody in Blue\" by asking \"what part of Rhapsody in Blue?,\u201d prompt on answers mentioning clarinet and \u201cRhapsody in Blue\u201d by asking \u201cwhat musical term is associated with that section?\u201d] ", "subcategory": "Music", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the clarinet glissando from \"Rhapsody in Blue\"</u></b> [both answers required, prompt on partial answer, prompt on \"Rhapsody in Blue\" by asking \"what part of Rhapsody in Blue?,\u201d prompt on answers mentioning clarinet and \u201cRhapsody in Blue\u201d by asking \u201cwhat musical term is associated with that section?\u201d]", "acceptable": ["the clarinet glissando from \"Rhapsody in Blue\""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The 50 daughters of this mortal represented the 50 months between each Olympics. This former resident of Mount Olympus received his punishment from Zeus for falling in love with Hera. This man\u2019s lover visited him every night in a cave on Mount Latmus. A 19th century adaptation of the myth of this man renames his lover to (*) \u201cCynthia.\u201d For 10 points, name this eternally-sleeping shepherd from Elis who was loved by Selene, the subject of a narrative poem by John Keats.", "answer": "Endymion ", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Endymion</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Endymion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Mach\u2019s principle connects these entities to the large-scale structure of the universe. A quantum form of these entities is split in two to avoid issues with the Heisenberg uncertainty principle. The derivative of angular velocity with respect to time crossed with position gives the Euler acceleration, a kind of fictitious force present in these entities. A (*) Galilean transformation changes between these entities using their relative velocity. Examples of these entities which are not accelerating are their inertial kind. For 10 points, name these entities, the conditions in which physical systems are observed.", "answer": "reference frame [frame of reference, anti-prompt on specific non-uniformly rotating reference frame kinds like inertial reference frame, non-inertial reference frame, rotating reference frame, , etc] ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>reference frame</u></b> [frame of reference, anti-prompt on specific non-uniformly rotating reference frame kinds like inertial reference frame, non-inertial reference frame, rotating reference frame, , etc]", "acceptable": ["reference frame"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A physician in this location decides \u201cYou wouldn't hang me? I thought not\u201d as he euthanizes a patient. In another poem, inhabitants of this location \u201cwent without the meat, and cursed the bread\u201d while resenting a wealthy resident. Another resident of this location sees two moons and sings (*) Auld Lang Syne. One structure in this location is described as \u201cshut and still\u201d though people \u201cstill stray around the sunken sill\u201d. For 10 points, name this fictional location whose residents include Eben Flood, Luke Havergal, and Richard Cory in the works of Edwin Arlington Robinson.", "answer": "Tilbury Town ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tilbury Town</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Tilbury Town"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: Two answers required. A leader of one of these two countries was forced to sign the Renville agreement to recognize puppet states set up by the other. One of these two countries invaded the other in Operation Product. One of these two countries partitioned the other via the Van Mook Line after one invasion. The United States threatened to cut off Marshall Plan aid to one of these two countries after it captured the other\u2019s capital of (*) Yogyakarta. For 10 points, name these two countries, one of which attempted to recapture Sukarno\u2019s country after its Dutch East India Company lost it. ", "answer": "the Netherlands AND Indonesia [prompt on partial answer, accept in either order] ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the Netherlands AND Indonesia</u></b> [prompt on <u>partial answer, accept in either order</u>]", "acceptable": ["the Netherlands AND Indonesia"], "promptable": ["partial answer, accept in either order"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The infamous \u201cAction Park\u201d featured one of these locations with a narrow loop-de-loop that visitors would often be stuck in. Wisconsin Dells, Wisconsin is sometimes referred to as the world capital of these locations and is home to one of them named for Noah\u2019s Ark. One of these locations features attractions such as \u201cHumunga Kowabunga\u201d and \u201cMayday Falls\u201d and is known as (*) Typhoon Lagoon, which is one of two of these locations at Walt Disney World. For 10 points, name these attractions where one might float on a lazy river or ride a water slide. ", "answer": "waterparks [prompt on \u201cparks\u201d alone, prompt on \u201ctheme parks\u201d or \u201camusement parks\u201d, antiprompt on \u201cwaterslide\u201d] ", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>waterparks</u></b> [prompt on <u>\u201cparks\u201d alone,</u> or <u>\u201ctheme parks\u201d</u> or <u>\u201camusement parks\u201d, antiprompt on \u201cwaterslide\u201d</u>]", "acceptable": ["waterparks"], "promptable": ["\u201cparks\u201d alone,", "\u201ctheme parks\u201d", "\u201camusement parks\u201d, antiprompt on \u201cwaterslide\u201d"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Varieties of the phrase \u201cMay the Lady of Gubla grant power to the king\u201d appear in 58 correspondences of this king with Rib-Hadda of Byblos. This ruler commissioned a series of cliff carvings known as the Boundary Stelae. Edward Ayrton discovered the remains of this ruler at (*) KV55. Three hundred letters written during this ruler\u2019s reign are known as the Amarna letters, named after his capital. This ruler wrote a \u201cGreat Hymn to\u201d a certain god represented by a solar disc. For 10 points, what Egyptian pharaoh founded the cult of Aten?", "answer": "Akhenaten [accept Amenhotep IV or Amenophis IV] ", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Akhenaten</u></b> [accept <b><u>Amenhotep IV</u></b> or <b><u>Amenophis IV</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Akhenaten", "Amenhotep IV", "Amenophis IV"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "While Schlegel diagrams are useful for preserving combinatorial and topological properties, they do not preserve these entities. In Schlafli notation, the second digit represents the number of these entities, and an isohedral figure is a polytope that is transitive with respect to these entities. Quasiregular polyhedra contain two different types of this entity. The (*) Euler characteristic is given in terms of the number of vertices, edges, and these entities. For 10 points, name these entities of which a cube has six.", "answer": "faces ", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>faces</u></b>", "acceptable": ["faces"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This location names a theory which claims the world population will drop to 2 billion by 2050. Some objects found at this location were collectively nicknamed \u201cJohnny\u2019s Child.\u201d Richard Hay established a chronology of this location\u2019s different sediments in his Geology of [this location]. This location, found in the Ngorongoro Conservation Area, contains remains of (*) Australopithecus boisei, Homo Habilis, and Homo Erectus. For 10 points, name this paleoanthropological site in Tanzania where Mary and Louis Leakey found tools and fossils from early Hominins.", "answer": "Olduvai Gorge ", "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Olduvai Gorge</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Olduvai Gorge"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A member of this family controversially featured a bright, psychedelic paint scheme designed by Peter Max at the 2000 Winston All Star Race. A member of this family\u2019s Dirty Mo Media company produces a podcast named after him. Fans hold up their fingers and go silent on lap (*) three of the Daytona 500 to honor a dead member of this family. A member of this family dedicated his win at the 2001 Pepsi 400 to his father who had died at the same track earlier in the year. For 10 points, name this North Carolina racing family that includes two men named Dale. ", "answer": "Earnhardt [accept Dale Earnhardt, accept Dale Earnhardt Jr.] ", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Earnhardt</u></b> [accept <b><u>Dale Earnhardt,</u></b> or <b><u>Dale Earnhardt Jr.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Earnhardt", "Dale Earnhardt,", "Dale Earnhardt Jr."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The creator of this activity wrote the treatise \u201cApogee and Decline of Counterpoint\u201d and was Bastian Perrot of Calw. Breaks from this activity allow a character to learn Chinese and improve relations with the Catholic church at (*) Marafiels monastery. Detractors of this activity such as Plinio Designori argue for a \u201creturn to the world\u201d from this activity in which participants connect music, math, and history. Magister Ludi is the director of, for 10 points, what title activity played by Joseph Knecht in a Herman Hesse novel?", "answer": "the glass bead game ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the glass bead game</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the glass bead game"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "To appease this being, the sorcerer Kunja Rana sacrificed his 9-year-old nephew in 2018. During the Kanya celebration, young girls are worshipped as this goddess. During a festival to this goddess, women smear each other\u2019s faces with a red powder in Sindoor Khela. This figure rode a lion to kill the Buffalo demon Mahishasura, resulting in the nine-night festival of (*) Navratri. For 10 points, name this primary aspect of Devi, celebrated in a namesake puja.", "answer": "Durga [prompt on Devi or Adi Parashakti; prompt on Parvati] ", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Durga</u></b> [prompt on <u>Devi</u> or <u>Adi Parashakti</u>; prompt on <u>Parvati</u>]", "acceptable": ["Durga"], "promptable": ["Devi", "Adi Parashakti", "Parvati"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An organomanganese compound known as MMT is used to increase one measure of this substance. The PONA number characterizes inputs to a process that primarily produces this substance using regenerator cyclones. Reid vapor pressure quantifies the volatility of this substance. The E10 form of this substance contains 10% of a certain additive. Compounds such as (*) MTBE and tetraethyl lead are used to prevent this substance\u2019s premature ignition in knocking. For 10 points, octane numbers characterize this substance refined from oil and used in cars.", "answer": "gasoline [prompt on gas; do not accept or prompt on \u201cdiesel\u201d, \u201cjet fuel\u201d, or other fuels] ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>gasoline</u></b> [prompt on <u>gas</u>; do not accept or prompt on \"\u201cdiesel\u201d, \u201cjet fuel\u201d,\" or \"other fuels\"]", "acceptable": ["gasoline"], "promptable": ["gas"], "rejectable": ["\u201cdiesel\u201d, \u201cjet fuel\u201d,", "other fuels"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "For many years, the Austin J. Tobin Plaza in this general place was the site of The Sphere, a massive bronze sculpture. Eighty-eight vertical searchlights comprise an annual installation in this place. A 2017 Visbal sculpture stood opposite a Di Modica statue in this place before being moved. The sculptures (*) Patience and Fortitude lie outside a library in this place, and Lee Lawrie\u2019s bronze Atlas is near the Rockefeller Center on this island. For 10 points, name this island home to the Charging Bull statue near the New York Stock Exchange.", "answer": "Manhattan [prompt on New York City; accept 9/11 Ground Zero until \u201cVisbal\u201d is read; accept NYC Financial District until \u201cPatience\u201d is read] ", "subcategory": "Painting", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Manhattan</u></b> [prompt on <u>New York City</u>; accept <b><u>9/11 Ground Zero until \u201cVisbal\u201d is read</u></b>; accept <b><u>NYC Financial District until \u201cPatience\u201d is read</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Manhattan", "9/11 Ground Zero until \u201cVisbal\u201d is read", "NYC Financial District until \u201cPatience\u201d is read"], "promptable": ["New York City"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One character in this play claims \u201cYou get right inside a man when you can wrap up in the smell of him\u201d while wearing another character\u2019s coat. One character in this play buys \u201cwhite\u201d clothes with money he has been saving for a farm to impress a girl who gets married before her planned visit to Port Elizabeth. The pen pal (*) Ethel Lange causes tensions between the two main characters of this play. For 10 points, name this play about the brothers Morris and Zachariah, by Athol Fugard.", "answer": "Blood Knot ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Blood Knot</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Blood Knot"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The protein LCAT begins one form of this process while reduced levels of PCSK9 promote this process. ApoA1 is a receptor on structures which transport the reactants of this process. Niemann-Pick disease stems from the inability of the lysosome to perform this process. Beta oxidation allows this process to continue in the (*) Krebs cycle which begins as bile salts dissolve the targets of this process. Lipases act in, for 10 points, what process that allows a class of macromolecules including triglycerides to be used for energy.", "answer": "lipid metabolism [prompt on metabolism or breakdown; accept specific types such as ganglioside metabolism, cholesterol metabolism, or fatty acid metabolism] ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>lipid metabolism</u></b> [prompt on <u>metabolism</u> or <u>breakdown</u>; accept <b><u>specific types such as ganglioside metabolism, cholesterol metabolism,</u></b> or <b><u>fatty acid metabolism</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["lipid metabolism", "specific types such as ganglioside metabolism, cholesterol metabolism,", "fatty acid metabolism"], "promptable": ["metabolism", "breakdown"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: the first line of this work is acceptable as an answer. A Micaela Wakil Janan prose translation of this work claims that \u201c[poets] have to live clean\u201d but poems can have \u201cspice and charm.\u201d This poem questions how critics can question the poet\u2019s manhood after hearing of his \u201cmany kisses.\u201d The writer of this poem brags that his poems can arouse even \u201chairy men who can't make their own loins stand upright.\u201d This (*) hendecasyllabic poem is addressed to \u201cFurius\u201d and \u201cAurelius.\u201d The narrator threatens to \u201cp\u0113d\u012bc\u0101bo\u201d and \u201cirrum\u0101b\u014d\u201d the addressees of, for 10 points, what vulgar poem by Gaius Valerius Catullus?", "answer": "Catullus Carmen 16 [accept \u201cP\u0113d\u012bc\u0101bo ego v\u014ds et irrum\u0101b\u014d\u201d or \u201cI Will Sodomize and Face Fuck You;\u201d accept similar clear knowledge equivalents; accept 16 alone after \u201cCatullus\u201d is read] ", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Catullus Carmen 16</u></b> [accept <b><u>\u201cP\u0113d\u012bc\u0101bo ego v\u014ds et irrum\u0101b\u014d\u201d</u></b> or <b><u>\u201cI Will Sodomize and Face Fuck You</u></b>; \u201d accept similar clear knowledge equivalents; accept <b><u>16 alone</u></b> after \u201cCatullus\u201d is read]", "acceptable": ["Catullus Carmen 16", "\u201cP\u0113d\u012bc\u0101bo ego v\u014ds et irrum\u0101b\u014d\u201d", "\u201cI Will Sodomize and Face Fuck You", "16 alone"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "These objects and an earthen bowl are paired in the title of an 1885 still life. In another, a woman \u201cseated before an open door\u201d performs an action with these objects in the town of Nuenen. The reverse of one painting depicting these objects, a member of the de Groot family, and a knife is Self Portrait with a (*) Straw Hat. In a painting of these objects, a clock reads seven and a single light source illuminates five Dutch peasants around a table consuming, for 10 points, these food items which are peeled and eaten in Van Gogh paintings.", "answer": "potatoes ", "subcategory": "Painting", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>potatoes</u></b>", "acceptable": ["potatoes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A fictional spy named Boniface was used to disguise the activities of this institution. The all female WRNS [WRENS] corps served as support staff at this institution during World War Two. Gordon Welchman developed \u201cbombes\u201d for this institution. This institution succeeded its country\u2019s (*) Room 40, which performed a similar function. This institution was made up of several huts where codebreaking was performed. For 10 points, name this home of the Government Code and Cypher School where Alan Turing helped break the Enigma code. ", "answer": "Bletchley Park [prompt on Government Code and Cypher School before mention] ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Bletchley Park</u></b> [prompt on <u>Government Code and Cypher School</u> before mention]", "acceptable": ["Bletchley Park"], "promptable": ["Government Code and Cypher School"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}]}